# **Greg Sandell**

#### Los Angeles, CA

(213) 479-0790 • GREG.SANDELL@GMAIL.COM • Portfolio/code: gregsandell.com

#### **About Me**

I provide client Web Application solutions of high quality and reliability using Javascript/Node.js/React Front End Development, Selenium-based Automated UI Testing, Salesforce Commerce Cloud eCommerce, load testing, SQL database design, asynchronous/multi-threaded processing, secure authentication, messaging, and integrating third party software. I have worked for enterprise clients in retail eCommerce, Real Estate, Executive Search, Healthcare, AdTech, Publishing, Finance, Defense, and Travel. I am also an accomplished classical pianist, electric bass player, and composer.

## **Experience**

OCT 2017 - PRESENT

**Crocs Inc.** — *Senior Front End Developer* 

- Javascript/web programmer in Salesforce Commerce Cloud (a.k.a. SFCC/DemandWare) for company eCommerce site with \$1.2 bil in 2019 sales
- Integrate SFCC with third party eCommerce services: PayPal, Givex giftcards, Adyen, CardConnect, Signal Tag Manager, Kount Fraud Manager, Olapic, Narvar, and Adobe Audience Manager analytics
- Support crocs.com sites in 8 different languages, 14 countries/locales, 7 payment processors
- Develop custom multi-tiered web applications including SQL, REST services, Ajax, token based authentication, pub/sub messaging, Bash shell scripts, AWS, and BrowserStack cloud components. Stack includes: Node.js, React/Redux, Express, Sqlite, WebSockets, Bootstrap, Material-UI.
- Develop reusable tools for UI automation and load testing; solve latency, asynchrony, and race condition issues; write CSS queries that work reliably across major mobile and desktop web browsers navigators.
- Provide Automated UI Test coverage for the eCommerce site including all phases of the purchase lifecycle, shopping cart interaction, product returns, payment processing, user profile and fraud detection. Tech stack: internJS, leadfoot, eureQa, BrowserStack cloud
- Provide training & mentoring to junior develoers on Javascript, Node.js and SFCC; give presentations to to developers and cross-functional teams on React and Automated UI Testing.
- Work with new fulfillment/distribution centers coming online by creating bulk test orders in the SAP Supply chain

AUG 2017 - NOV 2017

#### **UC Irvine / Trilogy Ed** — Part Time Course Instructor

• Instructor for "Fullstack Developer" bootcamp, teaching HTML, CSS, Git, Bootstrap, Javascript, jQuery, Ajax, Firebase, Node.js

APR 2016 - JUNE 2017

#### Ten-X, Irvine, CA - Sr. Software Engineer

- Developed presentation layer and application logic for hosted web application *auction.com*, a Real Estate auction transaction platform
- Responsible for features Search & Discovery, Event Details, Calendar, User prefs and personalization, and Home page written in AngularJS 1.4, React/Redux, ES6, ArcGIS, and Python

- Wrote QA Automation tests using Selenium and Nightwatch (demo: <a href="http://bit.ly/2wUjFcS">http://bit.ly/2wUjFcS</a>)
- Design and troubleshooting of REST and JSON-based backend, services, Omniture tracking to and LaunchDarkly feature flags

OCT 2015 - MAR 2016

## **John Deere, remote** - Front End Developer Consultant

- Developed AngularJS controllers, views, directives and services for hosted web application 'Sales Center', a 'build-a-Deere' tool for sales reps
- Wrote test coverage in Mocha, Sinon and Chai
- · Collaborated with Back End team on design and troubleshooting of REST/JSON-based services

NOV 2014 - AUG 2015

## **CyberCoders, Irvine, CA** - Front End Java Developer

- Developer for hosted web application 'Compass', a CRM platform for Recruiters.
- Created UI widgets and application logic for workflow tools in Sencha ExtJS 4.0.7 Javascript
- · Wrote backend Ajax/JSON components, test coverage in Jasmine, stress testing with jMeter

NOV 2013 - JUNE 2014

## Sears Holding Corporation, Chicago, IL - Developer

- Member of Core Mobile team supporting mobile version of sears.com E-Commerce site
- Wrote AngularJS controllers, views, and services, UIs in HTML5/CSS3 from Photoshop PSDs, REST web services in coordination.
- Launched mobile version of new fatures *Shop Your Way* (loyalty card) and *Shop Your Way Max* (Sears version of Amazon Prime).

AUG 2012 - AUG 2013

## Pathfinder Software (now orthogonal.io), Chicago, IL - Senior Software Engineer

- Wrote mobile apps (iPhone, iPad) for medical clients Kimberly-Clark, Haemonetics, and Amer. Assn. of Critical Care Nurses in hybrid web/iOS AngularJS and jQuery Mobile, Trigger.io, TestFlight, and Rails/Heroku
- Lead developer on iPhone app that was deployed in Apple AppStore (AACN Bedside)
- Lead developer for web-based census and demographic data-mining tool (MetroPulse Chicago: demo: <a href="http://bit.ly/2wU5Yun">http://bit.ly/2wU5Yun</a>)
- Lead developer on an iPad 'concierge' app to connect heart patients, their nurses and caregivers (ContinuCare) and a blood drive simulation sales tool for the iPad (Automated Whole Blood Collector)

APR 2010 - AUG 2012

## Truven Health Analytics, Chicago, IL - Senior Software Engineer

- Developed hosted web applications *CareDiscovery* and *IntegrationDiscovery*, Business Intelligence and data mining tools for a 4 TB Oracle OLAP Data Warehouse of Hospital Billing data
- Created servlet- and portal-based J2EE web applications for IBM Websphere Portal 5, Tomcat 6 & Glassfish in Java 1.4 & 6 Servlets, JSP, jQuery Javascript, PL/SQL stored procedures

## iCrossing, Chicago, IL - Senior Software Engineer

- Front End Developer for hosted web application Merchantize, an Ad Technology tool for managing clients'
  Paid Search campaigns, keyword purchases and cost-per-click advertising with major search and
  shopping engines (Google, Yahoo, MSN, NexTag, PriceGrabber)
- Consumed streaming XML-based product feeds for clients Sears, The Gap, Hilton, Lands End, LEGO, and Williams Sonoma with cron-based processes written in Perl, Bash, SMTP & Java.
- · Wrote PDF reports in Apache POI Java, cleaned product feeds and resolved Mysql data integrity issues

FEB 2008 - OCT 2008

## Chicago Tribune, Chicago, IL - Senior Internet Applications Developer

- Developed web software and content management behind all of Tribune Corp's newspaper, radio and television websites, including Chicago Tribune, LA Times, Red Eye.
- Developed code in Java 1.5 on J2EE platform including Oracle Application Server 10g, Oracle DB 10g, FAST search server, Sun Webserver (iPlanet) and TopLink 9.0 for web services.
- Created scheduled jobs for sweeping expired database content and JMeter test plans to simulate heavy load on high-profile chicagotribune.com website.

#### **Education**

### Northwestern University, Evanston, IL - PhD Music Theory

Cross-disciplinary curriculum including music theory, auditory perception, computer science and music synthesizer research. Dissertation: <a href="http://bit.ly/2wUbFZq">http://bit.ly/2wUbFZq</a>

## **Eastman School of Music, Rochester, NY** – MA Music Theory

Analysis techniques on classical and 20th Century music. Formal computer programming studies. Thesis on Edgard Varèse.

#### California State University, Los Angeles, CA – BM Piano Performance

Performed Junior and Senior recitals, placed in competitions, and performed Beethoven concerto with orchestra.

#### **Certifications**

March 2005: Sun Certified Web Component Developer for J2EE 1.4 (SCWCD)

Apr 2004: Sun Certified Programmer for the Java 2 Platform 1.4 (SCJP)

## References

Available on request.